Walter B. Goad Papers 1942-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.114
American Philosophical Society
Walter Goad Papers
1942-2000
Mss.Ms.Coll.114
American Philosophical Society
7.0 Linear feet
A physicist with the Theoretical Division of Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, Walter Goad became interested in molecular biology in the mid-1960s, devoting nearly all of his research to the analysis, storage and retrieval of information relating to nucleic acid sequences by the early 1970s. He was among the founders of GenBank, the world's first nucleic acid database, and was influential in the development of computational techniques for the analysis of DNA sequences. In the late 1980s, he served on the steering committee overseeing the establishment of the Human Genome Project. The Goad Papers relate primarily to the establishment and early operation of GenBank, the early phases of the Human Genome Project, and, more generally, to Goad's role as godfather of the new field of bioinformatics.
Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000
Index
Hildebrand, Carl E.
Hildebrand, Carl E.
Hillman, Dean E.
Hollister, Charlotte
Hood, Lee
Howard Hughes Medical Institute
Howey, Richard L.
Human Genome Organization
Human Genome Project
Human Genome Project
Human Genome Project
Human Genome Project
Human Genome Workshop (Santa Cruz, Calif., 1985)
Human Genome Workshop (Santa Cruz, Calif., 1985)
Hydrogen bomb
Inoue, Hideo
Intelligenetics
Intelligenetics
Intelligenetics
International CODATA Workshop (1st: 1987: Gaithersburg, Md.)
International Union of Biocheamistry. Nomenclature Committee
Isono, Katsumi
Jordan, Elke
Jordan, Elke
Jordan, Elke
Journal of Biological Chemistry
Journal of Virology
Kanehisa, Minoru
Kanehisa, Minoru
Heron, Elaine Jones
Blumberg, Baruch S., 1925-
Boats and boating
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bolt, Beranek, and Newman
Bradbury, Norris
Branscomb, Elbert W.
Brownstein, Charles
Brutlag, Douglas
Brutlag, Douglas
Brutlag, Douglas
Brutlag, Douglas
Burks, Christian
Burks, Christian
Burks, Christian
Burks, Christian
Burks, Christian
Burris, John
Buxton, R. S.
Cahill, George F.
Cahill, George F.
Cambridge University
>Cameron, Graham
Cantor, Charles R.
Cantor, Charles R.
Cantor, Charles R.
Carrano, Anthony V.
Cassatt, James
Cassatt, James
Chinese--United States
Chromosome mapping
Chromosome mapping
Claverie, J.-M.
CODATA
CODATA
CODATA
CODATA
Comings, David E.
Comings, David E.
Complex Carbohydrate Structure Data Base Workshop (1987: Auburn, N.Y.)
Computers
Coulson, A. F. W.
Cummings, Michael
Dana-Farber Cancer Institute
Databases
Davidson, Daniel B.
Dayhoff, Margaret O.
Dayhoff, Margaret O.
Dayhoff, Margaret O.
DeLisi, Charles
DeVita, Vincent T.
Escherichia coli
Escherichia coli
European Molecular Biology Laboratory
European Molecular Biology Laboratory
European Molecular Biology Laboratory
European Molecular Biology Laboratory
European Molecular Biology Laboratory
Exploring the Role of Robotics and Automation in Decoding the Human Genome (1987: Santa Fe)
Federal Bureau of Investigation
Federation of American Scientists
Feigenbaum, Edward A.
Fickett, James W.
Fickett, James W.
Fickett, James W.
Fitch, Walter M.
Friedland, P.
Fripp, W.
Gelinas, Richard
GenBank
GenBank
GenBank
GenBank
GenBank
GenBank
GenBank
Gene mapping
Gene mapping
Gene mapping
Gene mapping
Genomics
Genomics
Genomics
Genomics
Genomics
Genomics
Genomics
Gilbert, Walter
Goad, Maxine S.
Goad, Maxine S.
Goad, Maxine S.
Goldstein, Byron
Hamm, Greg H.
Hamm, Greg H.
Hamm, Greg H.
Hearst, John E.
Heart, Frank E.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bell, George I.
Bilofsky, Howard S.
Bioinformatics
Bioinformatics
Bitensky, Mark
Bitensky, Mark
Bitensky, Mark
Bitensky, Mark
Blumberg, Baruch S., 1925-
Anderson, Norman
Apirion, David
Anderson, N. Leigh
American Type Culture Collection
Kashdan, Maurice
Kedes, Lawrence
Kerr, Donald M.
King, Donald West
Kingsbury, David
Knight, Gary A.
Kohara, Yuji
Laboratory of Mathematical Biology
Lathe, Richard
Lee, Wen Ho
Lee, Wen Ho
Leenart, Frieda
Lehrach, Hans
Lerman, Leonard
Lerman, Leonard
Lerman, Leonard S.
Levine, Arnold
Lind, David A.
Lindbergh, Donald A. B.
Loehr, John Joseph
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Group T-10
Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory. Group T-10
Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.)
Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.)
Mark, J. Carson
Martinez, Hugo
Maruyama, Takeo
Maxam, Allan M.
McDonnell, Michael T.
Messing, Joachim
Mitra, Sankar
Molecular biology
Molecular biology
Molecular evolution
Molecular genetics
Moyzis, Robert K.
Moyzis, Robert K.
Murray, Ken
Murray, Ken
Myers, Gerald
National Cancer Institute. Laboratory of Mathematical Biology
National Institute of General Medical Sciences
National Institute of General Medical Sciences
National Institutes of Health
National Institutes of Health
National Institutes of Health
National Institutes of Health
National Institutes of Health
National Research Council (U.S.). Numerical Data Advisory Board
National Research Council (U.S.). Numerical Data Advisory Board
National Research Council (U.S.). Numerical Data Advisory Board
National Research Council. Committee on Biotechnology Nomenclature and Information
National Science Foundation
National Science Foundation. Advisory Committee on Advanced Computing
Nuclear arms control
Nucleic acid probes
Nucleic acid probes
Nucleic Acid Sequence Data Bank Workshop (1980: Bethesda, Md.)
Nucleotide sequence
Nucleotide sequence
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Nucleotide sequence--Data processing
Ooi, Tatsuo
Overton, Christian
Ozeki, Haruo
Pagano, Marcello
Palaniappan, K.
Plants--Genetics
Policansky, David
Polymerase Chain Reaction
PROPHET System
PROPHET System
Puck, Theodore T.
Puck, Theodore T.
Puck, Theodore T.
Puck, Theodore T.
Puck, Theodore T.
Puck, Theodore T.
Rabson, Alan
Recombinant DNA
Roberts, Richard J.
Roberts, Richard J.
Roberts, Richard J.
Robinson, Arthur
Robotics
Robotics
Robotics
Ruddle, Frank H.
Sailing--British Columbia
Sailing--Gulf of California
Salser, Winston
Sillerud, Laurel O.
Sinsheimer, Robert L.
Sirotkin, Karl
Sirotkin, Karl
Smith, David A.
Smith, G. P.
Smith, Hamilton O.
Smith, Temple F.
Smith, Temple F.
Smith, Temple F.
Smith, Temple F.
Spies--China
Spies--China
Sprinzl, Matthias
Stein, Gary
Stein, Janet
Strategic Defence Initiative
Strategic Defence Initiative
Stuber, Kurt
Supercomputers
Supercomputers
Supercomputers
Supercomputers
Supercomputers
Supercomputers
Sutton, H. Eldon
Symposium on Biological Applications on Cray Supercomputers (1987: Houston, Tex.)
Symposium on the Analysis of Genetic Squences (1984: New York, N.Y.)
Tabor, Herbert
Teller, Edward, 1908-
Thomas, Charles A.
Topiol, Sid
Torney, David C.
Ulam, Stanislaw, 1904-1984
United States Public Health Service
United States. Office of Technology Assessment
United States. Office of Technology Assessment
USERNET
Wada, Akiyoshi
Wada, Akiyoshi
Wakeford, Richard
Walker, Richard T.
Walters, Ron
Ward, David C.
Watanabe, Utaru
Waterman, Michael S.
Watson, Chuch
Weinstein, Harel
Whitlock, David G.
Williams, Mary Louise
Workshop on Algorithms for Molecular Genetics (1988: Bethesda, Md.)
Separated Materials note
Two posters and a scrapbook are housed with oversized materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Goad Papers were donated to the APS in 2001 by Maxine S. Goad, through Chris Goad and Baruch Blumberg.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Walter Goad, a nuclear physicist from Los Alamos Labs and pioneer in bioinformatics, consist of six linear feet of materials documenting the founding of GenBank and the early phases of the Human Genome Project. Bringing the quantitative skills of a physicist to bear on the problem of the analysis, storage and retrieval of molecular biological information, Goad was instrumental in the creation of the first nucleic acid sequence databank.
The collection is oriented almost exclusively toward the phase of Goad's career after he had taken up molecular biology. Apart from a small number of letters dating from the early 1940s, when Goad was seeking his first job, and an interesting response to the Federation of American Scientists' statement on hydrogen bomb testing from 1953, there is nothing to document his career prior to his conversion to DNA. The relatively limited correspondence (0.5 linear feet) in the Series I is primarily personal in nature, however Goad's extensive exchanges with his friend, Nobel laureate Sidney Altman, reveals a great deal about their mutual scientific interests and attitudes. Goad's stand on behalf of his Los Alamos colleague, Wen Ho Lee, accused of providing sensitive information on nuclear weapons to the People's Republic of China, is well documented.
Series II consists of correspondence, manuscripts, documents, notes, and printed materials directly or indirectly relating to GenBank, including planning documents, contracts for the construction of the databank, materials documenting the role of Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory in facilitating the project, information on "competitors" and colleagues, workshops and conferences, and correspondence with Bolt, Baranek and Newman, the contractor for database construction and distribution (and the firm who developed ARPANET, networking routers, and email, as well as introducing the @ sign).
Goad's role in the Human Genome Project was smaller, though still important, and Series III includes approximately one linear foot of manuscripts, correspondence, and notes relating to meeting of the Human Genome Project steering committee in the project's planning phases.
Series I. Correspondence and notes, 1942-2000 (1 box; 0.5 linear feet)
Series II. Works by Goad, 1953-2000 (1 box; 0.5 linear feet)
Series III. GenBank materials, 1979-1987 (4 boxes; 2 linear feet)
Series IV. Human Genome Project, 1983-1993 (2 boxes; 1 linear foot)
Series V. Conferences and workshops, 1980-1988 (2 boxes; 1 linear foot)
Series VI. Biographical and personal, 1942-2001 (1 box; 1 linear foot)
Series VII. Miscellaneous and photographs, 1945-2000 (1 box; 1 linear foot)
Biographical/Historical note
From his roots in the red clay soil of rural Georgia during the Depression, Walter Goad went on to a distinguished career in two disparate fields: nuclear weapons design and bioinformatics. Having lived in various towns in Georgia and graduating from Grainger High School in Kinston, N.C., in 1942, Goad set out to become a radio technician and expand his horizons by heading north for the first time. As would be true throughout his early years, his experience would be brief, but fruitful. Shortly after accepting a position with a station in Schenectady, N.Y., Goad was taken under the wing of his employer, who steered him toward college, helping arrange a scholarship at nearby Union College to make it all possible.
With America's entry in the Second World War, however, Goad's college plans changed. At the end of his freshman year, when he became eligible for the draft, Goad enlisted in the Navy and earned a spot in the V-12 officers' training program. The program allowed Goad, along with a small number of other candidates that included Baruch Blumberg, to continue toward his B.S. in physics, which he was awarded in the spring of 1945, just as the war was ending in Europe. His subsequent military career was nearly as brief as his career in radio. After an additional four months of training at midshipman's school in Annapolis, Goad was detached to the Pacific to complete his military obligation aboard a submarine chaser. By the following spring, his service was no longer needed, and he returned home to enter the University of California, Berkeley, as one of the horde of returning veterans pursuing a graduate degree in physics. The departure of Robert Oppenheimer later that year, however, took the luster off of Berkeley and as the appeal of the overtaxed program waned, Goad decided to transfer to Duke to work under the up and coming Lothar Nordheim on a project eventually titled A Theoretical Study of Extensive Cosmic Ray Air Showers (1954).
Yet again, Goad's path shifted. During the Spring 1950, Nordheim took a leave of absence to work at Los Alamos National Laboratory, inviting Goad to accompany him and complete his dissertation in New Mexico. Assigned to work with the Theoretical Division, Goad's first priority was to complete his dissertation, but he rapidly became a valued member of the design team working on the hydrogen bomb (he witnessed the first test on Eniwetok (Enewetak) Atoll in November 1952), and except for two sabbatical years, never again left the Laboratory. Goad's association with Los Alamos was personal, as well as professional: in 1952, he met and married Maxine Steineke, a graduate student in physics from Stanford working at the Laboratory with whom he had three children.
Although Goad's residence was firmly settled, his intellectual interests gradually evolved. By the early 1960s, he and a small number of colleagues at Los Alamos began to take up an interest in the emerging field of molecular biology. Spending a sabbatical year at the University of Colorado medical school (1964-1965) to strengthen his knowledge of the field, Goad began to apply himself to the challenges posed by the rapid accumulation of nucleic acid data, and after another sabbatical at the Laboratory of Molecular Biology in Cambridge, England (1970-1971), he turned his full efforts to molecular research. When George Bell created group T-10 at Los Alamos (Theoretical Biology and Biophysics) in 1974, Goad became one of its charter members.
To molecular biology, Goad brought a suite of quantitative skills and a strong knowledge of computing. As early as the late 1960s, he made efforts to address the problems associated with the storage, retrieval, and analysis of molecular data, conceiving of the computer as a central tool for collaborative and analytical work in molecular biology. Following a 1979 meeting at the Rockefeller University to discuss how these data could be managed and exploited, Goad and his Los Alamos colleagues established the Los Alamos Sequence Data Bank and began to develop software for sequence analysis. Goad conceived of expanding the database nationally and internationally.
With funding from the National Institute of General Medical Sciences (NIGMS), among other agencies, the core facility at Los Alamos was expanded in collaboration with Bolt, Baranek, and Newman (BBN, the firm that had handled the construction of ARPANet in the late 1960s), and in 1982, the database was rechristened GenBank. The base of its operations remained at Los Alamos, as it was operated successively under the control of BBN (1982-1987), IntelliGenetics (1987-1992), and (since 1992) the National Center for Biotechnology Information. Goad also helped to establish a strong working relationship with parallel efforts in Europe (the European Molecular Biology Laboratory, EMBL) and Japan (DNA Database of Japan, DDBJ).
The success of GenBank in turn laid much of the groundwork for the Human Genome Project which followed in the late 1980s and 1990s. Begun formally in 1990 as an effort to identify, map, and sequence all of the genes in the human genome, the Human Genome Project benefited both conceptually and practically from GenBank, and Goad was an early member of the the Human Genome Advisory Panel.
For his efforts on behalf of GenBank, Goad received a Los Alamos National Laboratory Distinguished Service Award, and the Laboratory bestowed its highest honor, making him a Laboratory Fellow. He was also a Fellow of the American Physical Society and the American Association for the Advancement of Science. Walter Goad died of a stroke in Santa Fe on November 2, 2000.
Altman, Sidney, 1939-; Bell, George I.; Bitensky, Mark; Blumberg, Baruch S., 1925-; Bolt, Baranek and Newman; Brutlag, Douglas; Burks, Christian; Cantor, Charles R.; CODATA; Comings, David E.; Dayhoff, Margaret O.; European Molecular Biology Laboratory; Federal Bureau of Investigation; Fickett, James W.; Fitch, Walter M.; GenBank; Gilbert, Walter; Goad, Maxine S.; Intelligenetics; Jordan, Elke; Kanehisa, Minoru; Lee, Wen Ho; Lerman, Leonard; Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory.; Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.).; Maxam, Allan M.; Moyzis, Robert K.; Puck, Theodore T., (Theodore Thomas), 1916-2005; Roberts, Richard J.; Smith, Temple F.; Teller, Edward, 1908-2003; Wada, Akiyoshi; Bioinformatics; Gene mapping; Genomics; Human Genome Project; Hydrogen bomb; Molecular biology; Molecular genetics; Nucleic acid probes; Nucleotide sequence--Data processing; Polymerase Chain Reaction; Strategic Defense Initiative; Supercomputers
- Series I. Correspondence and notes, 1942-2000
  Scope and Contents note
  Miscellaneous correspondence, reports, and legal documents of both a professional and personal nature. The most extensive body of correspondence consists of numerous email exchanges with Sidney Altman, a close friend and 1989 Nobel laureate in chemistry, and there are less extensive exchanges with Nobel laureates Baruch Blumberg and Max Perutz. While the correspondence with Altman is largely personal, both correspondents touch on a wide range of topics, from Ernst Mayr's alleged antipathy to molecular biology to hierarchical theories of evolution to current politics.
  Goad's annual progress reports to Los Alamos provide interesting insight into the evolution of his views on molecular biology between the late 1960s and mid-1970s when his commitment to the field was consolidated and when he moved into Los Alamos group T-10, Theoretical Biology and Biophysics. Equally important is a series of files relating to what might have been the highest profile event of his career: his efforts on behalf of his Los Alamos colleague, Wen Ho Lee, who had been accused of supplying secret information about nuclear weapons research to the People's Republic of China. Goad took a prominent role in marshalling support among scientists and in the media, and supplied an affidavit (his "declaration") on behalf of Lee at trial.
  - Altman, Sidney, 1939-, 1997-2000; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Correspondence, primarily e-mail, with Nobel laureate Sidney Altman
    - Folder 1, 1997
    - Folder 2, 1998-2000
  - Bell, G. I. and Walter Goad, 1980 December 4; 2p. (Box 1)
    Memo to R. Ewald. Prospective National DNA Sequence Library and Analysis Center needs External Computer Network Access to CCF
  - Bingham, Jeff, 1987; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Blumberg, Baruch S., 1925-, 1988, 1992; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Brownell, Robert, 1970, 1983; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Carruthers, Peter, 1974, 1981; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Davis, Joel, 1988; 3p. (Box 1)
  - Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000, 1942-2000; 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Correspondence regarding first job, 1942; 4 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
    - Los Alamos reports, 1969; 1 item; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      List of Goad's publications in theoretical biology
    - Los Alamos reports, 1972; 8 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes TMs "Numerical Analysis of Gel Permeation Chromatograms" (2 copies); "Macromolecular Diffusion" (2 copies); letter to LASL; and "Progress Abstract;" and note to contributors to Enzyme-Structure part D
    - Los Alamos reports, 1973; 5 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes Progress Abstract; TMs "Analysis of Experiments in Radiation Chemistry of DNA"; review of Foundations of Mathematical Biology.
    - Los Alamos reports, 1974; 6 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes Progress Abstract ("Radiation Chemistry of Nucleic Acids"); two office memos; list Publications on Theoretical Biology and Biophysics; and vita of Walter Goad; "Two Research Problems" ("Epidemiology" and "Fundamental Studies of Diffusion")
    - Los Alamos reports, 1975; 4 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes Progress Abstract; list of Publications on Theoretical Biology and Biophysics (2 copies); review of book "Introduction to Mathematical Biology"
    - Los Alamos reports, 1976; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes three copies of T-10 Publciations FY-76.
    - Los Alamos reports, 1977; 2 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes report on activities of T-10 (Theoretical Biology and Biophysics) and vita of Walter
    - Los Alamos reports and miscellany, 1978-2000; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
      Includes "publications FY78"; report for T-10, 1983; computer printout (ca.1983?) on sequence alignment algorithm; photocopy of Los Alamos Administrative Manual, 1987; program for Goad's funeral service, 2000
    - Reprint requests, 1987, 1989; 2 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 1)
  - Kanehisa, Minoru, Roberts, Richard J., 1943-, 1991, 2000 (Box 1)
  - King Faisal International Prize, 1987; 2p. (Box 1)
  - Lee, Wen Ho, 2000; 5 folders (Box 1)
    Includes copy of indictment against Lee.
    - Appreciation of Walter Goad's contribution to the case of Wen Ho Lee, 2000; 15p.; Lee, Wen Ho (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence 1, 2000; 85p.; Lee, Wen Ho (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence 2, 2000; Lee, Wen Ho (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence 3, 2000; 56p.; Lee, Wen Ho (Folder 4)
    - Declaration of Walter Goad, 2000; 11p.; Lee, Wen Ho (Folder 5)
  - Perelson, Alan S., 2000 August; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Perutz, Max, 1914-, 1993; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Rabson, Alan S., 1986 September 19; 14p. (Box 1)
    Site report for Laboratory of Mathematical Biology
  - Studer, Frank, 1982-1995; 5 items (Box 1)
  - United States. Department of Energy, 1993 October; 4p. (Box 1)
  - United States. Selective Service System, 1956; 4 items (Box 1)
  - University of Colorado, 1964-1977; 23 items (Box 1)
  - Wada, Akiyoshi, 1982 October; 2p. (Box 1)
    Re: cooperation between GenBank and similar databank in Japan
  - Watanabe, Utaru, 1982 September 13; 1p. (Box 1)
- Series II. Works by Goad
  Selected works, published and semi-published, by Goad from throughout his career. These include a copy of his dissertation, A Theoretical Study of Extensive Cosmic Ray Air Showers (Duke University, 1954), articles (not separately inventoried), book reviews, and reviews of grant and research proposals by peers.
  - A Theoretical Study of Extensive Cosmic Ray Air Showers, 1953; 117p.; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
    Dissertation, Duke University
  - Publications 1, 1952-1965; 10 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
  - Publications 2, 1968-1977; 16 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
  - Publications 3, 1978-1981; 4 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
    Includes unsolicited "Proposal to Establish a National Center for Collection, and Computer Storage and Analysis of Nucleic Acid Sequences" submitted by T-10
  - Publications 4, 1982-1983; 5 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
  - Publications 5, 1984-1989; 9 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
    Includes copy of Goad's article "Sequence Analysis: Contributions by Ulam to Molecular Genetics," 1989.
  - Book reviews, 1965-1982; 5 items; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
  - Peer reviews, 1981-1988; ca.100p.; Goad, Walter B., 1925-2000 (Box 2)
- Series III. GenBank